<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Installing_CloudForms_on_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_OpenStack_Platform.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Running_OpenStack_on_CloudForms_Management_Engine" remap="TID_25052">
	<title>Launching the CloudForms Management Engine Instance</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Launch a CloudForms Management Engine Instance on OpenStack</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the OpenStack Dashboard, in the <guilabel>Project</guilabel> tab, click <guimenuitem>Instances</guimenuitem> under the <guimenu>Compute</guimenu> menu. <!-- Select the custom made flavor for your instance. The flavor selected determines the compute resources available to your instance. The specific resources for the flavor selected are displayed in the flavor Details pane for you to preview.-->
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Launch Instance</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter a name for the instance. <!--See the <citetitle>Red Hat Enterprise Linux OpenStack Platform Getting Started Guide</citetitle> for further instructions regarding access and security.-->
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the custom flavor for your instance. The flavor selection determines the computing resources available to your instance. The resources used by the flavor are displayed in the <guimenuitem>Flavor Details</guimenuitem> pane.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter <literal>1</literal> in the <guilabel>Instance Count</guilabel> field.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select a boot option from the <guilabel>Instance Boot Source</guilabel> list: 
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Boot from image</guilabel> - displays a new field for <guilabel>Image Name</guilabel>. Select the image from the drop-down list.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Boot from snapshot</guilabel> - displays a new field for <guilabel>Instance Snapshot</guilabel>. Select the snapshot from the drop-down list.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Boot from volume</guilabel> - displays a new field for <guilabel>Volume</guilabel>. Select the volume from the drop-down list.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Boot from image (creates a new volume)</guilabel> - boot from an image and create a volume by choosing <guilabel>Device Size</guilabel> and <guilabel>Device Name</guilabel> for your volume. Some volumes can be persistent. To ensure the volume is deleted when the instance is deleted, select <guilabel>Delete on Terminate</guilabel>.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para> 
							<guilabel>Boot from volume snapshot (creates a new volume)</guilabel> - boot from a volume snapshot and create a new volume by choosing <guilabel>Volume Snapshot</guilabel> from the drop-down list and adding a <guilabel>Device Name</guilabel> for your volume. Some volumes can be persistent. To ensure the volume is deleted when the instance is deleted, select <guilabel>Delete on Terminate</guilabel>.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guilabel>Networking</guilabel> and select a network for the instance by clicking the <guibutton>+</guibutton> (plus) button for the network from <guilabel>Available Networks</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Launch</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>