<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Creating_Reports_and_Feeds.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Adding_a_Report" remap="TID_15461">
	<title>Adding a Report</title>
	<para>
		Add reports if the default reports do not include what you need or you want to narrow the scope of a report. For example, you may want a report that shows only Windows virtual machines.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Add a Report</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu><guisubmenu>Reports</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> accordion.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), then click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Add a New Report</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guimenu>Columns</guimenu> tab, edit the <guilabel>Basic Report Info</guilabel> area.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2287.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Type a unique name in <guilabel>Menu Name</guilabel> for how you want the report described in the menu list.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Type the <guilabel>Title</guilabel> you want displayed on the report in title.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Add fields in the <guilabel>Configure Report Columns</guilabel> area.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2288.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Base the report on</guilabel> table dropdown to choose a table to get fields from.
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							If you change the report base or the interval, all selections below will be reset.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select fields that you want in the report from <guilabel>Available Fields</guilabel>, and then click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2289.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Move selected fields down)</guibutton>. In addition to the fields, you can also select any tags that you have created and assigned.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Change the order of the fields in the report by clicking 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2290.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Move selected fields up)</guibutton> or 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2289.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Move selected fields down)</guibutton>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Consolidation</guimenu> tab to consolidate and aggregate data points into maximum, minimum, average, and total. Specifically, this would be useful for analyzing performance data over a specific period of time. Note that if you do this, you will not see individual records, but rather the calculation as a column header.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2291.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select the columns to group by.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2292.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						For each numeric field selected in the report, you can click the dropdown under <guilabel>Calculations</guilabel>. Check the calculations you want to use.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Formatting</guimenu> tab to set the size of paper for a PDF and column header format.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						From the <guilabel>PDF Output</guilabel> area, select the page size from the dropdown.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2293.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						From <guilabel>Specify Column Headers and Formats</guilabel>, type the text you want displayed for each field. For each numeric field, you can also set the numeric format.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2294.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guilabel>Styling</guilabel> tab to change the color of the text or the background for a row based on a condition.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2295.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use Style to select the format for the value, you can choose to change the text color or the background.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use If to create a conditional statement for the style.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Filter</guimenu> tab to set filters for the data displayed in the report. There are two types of filters: the first is the <guilabel>Record Filter</guilabel> which is the primary filter of the main tables records, the second is also a <guilabel>Display Filter</guilabel>, which is a secondary filter of rows based on the fields of the child table. Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1851.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> in the appropriate area to use the expression editor to choose the appropriate options for your criteria. Based on what you choose, different options will show.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Field</guilabel> to create criteria based on field values.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2296.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Count of</guilabel> to create criteria based on the count of something, such as the number of snapshots for a Virtual Machine, or the number of Virtual Machines on a Host.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2297.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Tag</guilabel> to create criteria based on tags assigned to your resources. For example, you may want to check the power state of a virtual machine or see if it is tagged as production.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2298.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Registry</guilabel> to create criteria based on registry values. For example, you may want to check if DCOM is enabled on a Windows System. Note that this applies only to Windows operating systems.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2299.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Find</guilabel> to seek a particular value, and then check a property. For example, finding the Admin account and checking that it is enabled.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2300.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/1863.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Commit Expression Element Changes)</guibutton> to add the expression.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>
					The filters that you apply will show at the bottom of the report so that you know which filters have been applied.
				</para>
			</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Summary</guimenu> tab to select sort order, sort type, groupings, and group calculations for the report. Summary groups rows of data based on the sort breaks. You can only sort by fields that display in the report.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2301.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Set the primary sort in <guilabel>Sort the Report by</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Set the next sorts in <guilabel>Within Above Field, Sort By</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select the type of sort, ascending or descending, in <guilabel>Sort order</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In <guilabel>Show Sort breaks</guilabel>, select <guimenuitem>Yes</guimenuitem> to show the sort breaks, <guimenuitem>Counts</guimenuitem> to show sort breaks with the count, or <guimenuitem>No</guimenuitem> for no sort breaks.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2302.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						For any numeric field, you can select to show minimum, average, maximum, and total in the sort break.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Charts</guimenu> tab to create a chart for the report. This is not required.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2303.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Choose a chart type</guilabel> to select a type of chart. Note that some charts may not produce the result you are looking for based on the types of fields in the report and its sort order.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you only want to see the top values, select the number of top values from <guilabel>Top values to show</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you want to see the total number of values that are not categorize and evaluate to other, check <guilabel>Sum 'Other' values</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guimenu>Timeline</guimenu> tab to select a timeline for the report. You must have a field of time or date format to use this feature.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2304.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Base Timeline on</guilabel> to select a column in date or time format for the report.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select a unit of time for the first band in <guilabel>First band unit</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select a unit of time for the second band in <guilabel>Second band unit</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select a unit of time for the third band in <guilabel>Third band unit</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select an <guilabel>Event to position at</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select the range for the event to position from <guilabel>Show events from last</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<note>
				<para>
					If you select a timeline for a report, that timeline will also show on the timelines page of <guilabel>Cloud Intelligence</guilabel>. The filters that you apply will show on a timeline report so that you know which filters have been applied.
				</para>
			</note>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guilabel>Previews</guilabel> tab to see a sample of your report.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				When you have the report that you want, click <guibutton>Add</guibutton> to create the new report.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<note>
		<para>
			After the new report is created, to make the report accessible from the report menu, you must add it to a report menu.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>