<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Control_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_create_a_Real_Time_Performance_Alert" remap="TID_14822">
	<title>Creating a Real Time Performance Alert</title>
	<para>
		Real Time Performance alerts enables you to be notified immediately when a performance threshold has been met for a virtual machine, host, or cluster. Capacity and Utilization must be enabled for performance thresholds to be detected. See <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/CloudForms/3.2/html/Settings_and_Operations_Guide/index.html"><citetitle>CloudForms Management Engine Settings and Operations Guide</citetitle></ulink> for instructions.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a Real Time Performance Alert</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to menu:Control[Explorer].
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the [label]#Alert# accordion, then click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Add a new Alert</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Info</guilabel> area:
			</para>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<para>
						Type in a <guilabel>Description</guilabel> for the alert.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						From <guilabel>Based On</guilabel>, select <guilabel>VM and Instance</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						For <guilabel>What to Evaluate</guilabel>, select <guilabel>Real Time Performance</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						In <guilabel>Notification Frequency</guilabel>, select how often you want to be notified if the performance threshold is reached.
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Set the threshold in the <guilabel>Real Time Performance Parameters</guilabel> area.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1978.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<para>
						From <guilabel>Performance Field</guilabel>, select the field to check and any other parameters required for that field.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						In <guilabel>And is Trending</guilabel>, select <guilabel>Don't Care</guilabel> if it does not matter how the performance metric is trending. Otherwise, choose from the possible trending options.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						In <guilabel>Field Meets Criteria for</guilabel>, select the amount of time that the threshold requires to be met to trigger the alert.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Set <guilabel>Debug Tracing</guilabel> to true only when directed to do so by Red Hat Support. This provides an extremely detailed level of logging and can result in many more log lines being written.
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				After setting the parameters, you then select what you want the alert to do. You can send an email, create an SNMP Trap, let the alert show on the timeline, or send a management event to start an automation process. <!--See Creating an Alert.-->
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>