<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Cloud_Intelligence">
	<title>Cloud Intelligence</title> 
	<para>
		Cloud Intelligence shows your virtual environments events, reports, and configurable alerts. This information supports better information technology decision making and predictions for future virtual machine management.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Dashboard">
		<title>Dashboard</title> 
		<para>
			When you log in to the console, it brings you directly to the <guilabel>Cloud Intelligence Dashboard</guilabel> page by default. The console uses widgets to organize this page, providing you with a default set of commonly used widgets. The configuration items on these widgets are clickable allowing you to drill down directly to a referenced item.
		</para>
		<para>
			Customize this page to include the charts, reports, and RSS feeds you specifically want to see as soon as you log in to the console. You can add, remove, move, minimize, zoom into, and maximize widgets. Only users with the proper access can create widgets.
		</para>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_add_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_reset_to_the_default_set_of_widgets.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_remove_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_zoom_in_to_a_chart_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_open_a_chart_or_report_widget_in_its_own_window.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_minimize_or_maximize_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_download_a_report_widget_as_a_file.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Creating_Dashboard_Widgets">
		<title>Creating Dashboard Widgets</title>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_Report_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_Chart_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_an_RSS_Feed_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_Menu_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_edit_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_copy_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_delete_a_widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Importing_a_Widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Exporting_a_Widget.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_generate_widget_content_immediately.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Reports">
		<title>Reports</title> 
		<para>
			Click the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> accordion under <menuchoice><guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu><guisubmenu>Reports</guisubmenu></menuchoice> to see a list of reports available. These reports have been constructed to help you view the most commonly requested and significant data. From here, you can also create reports if you have appropriate access. <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> provides a large group of default reports organized into categories. Each category has its own set of subfolders.
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Configuration Management</guilabel> to see hardware, application, network, service, user account, operating system, and snapshot information for all of your items.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Migration Readiness</guilabel> to see information specifically related to items required to migrate a virtual machine.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Operations</guilabel> to look at free space on registered and unregistered virtual machines, to see power states for virtual machines, and see which offline virtual machines have snapshots or have never been analyzed. You are also provided with reports specifically related to the operation of <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname>, such as user ids and snapshots taken by <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>VM Sprawl</guilabel> to check on usage information and disk waste.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> to see virtual machine, folder, and cluster relationships.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Events</guilabel> to view operations and configuration management events.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Performance by Asset Type</guilabel> to see a report on the performance of your virtual infrastructure. You must be capturing capacity and utilization data to get this information.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Use <guilabel>Running Processes</guilabel> to view the information on processes running on a virtual machine. You must have domain credentials entered for the zone to collect the info for these reports, and the virtual machine must have been analyzed at least once.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> 
					<guilabel>Trending</guilabel> shows projections of datastore capacity and host CPU and memory use.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> 
					<guilabel>Provisioning</guilabel> shows provisioning activity based on the approver, datastore, requester, and virtual machine.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			For a complete list of Reportable Fields in CloudForms Management Engine see <xref linkend="appe-Reportable_Fields_in_CloudForms_Management_Engine" />
		</para>
		<section id="sect-Running_Reports">
			<title>Running Reports</title> 
			<para>
				There are two different ways to generate a report: either scheduling the report, or manually by clicking the report generation button on the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> page. <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> uses interactive report generation so that reports are placed on a queue. A visual indicator of the reports status is shown. All reports are automatically saved so that they can be downloaded and analyzed later.
			</para>
			<xi:include href="topics/To_generate_a_single_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_schedule_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_modify_a_report_schedule.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_run_a_scheduled_report_immediately.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		</section>
		<section id="sect-Viewing_Reports">
			<title>Viewing Reports</title> 
			<para>
				Once you have created a schedule for a report, you can view it at any time after the first scheduled time has occurred.
			</para>
			<procedure>
				<title>To View a Report</title>
				<step>
					<para>
						Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu><guisubmenu>Reports</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Click the <guimenu>Saved Reports</guimenu> accordion or the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> accordion.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Click on the instance of the report you want to view.
					</para>
				</step>
			</procedure>
			<xi:include href="topics/Changing_Report_Views.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/Report_Download_Buttons.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/Downloading_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/Showing_a_Report_in_Full_Screen.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		</section>
		<xi:include href="topics/Adding_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Copying_a_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Editing_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Deleting_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_import_a_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_export_a_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<section id="sect-Report_Menus">
			<title>Report Menus</title> 
			<para>
				By default, all account roles have the same reports available. If you have the super administrator or administrator role, you can customize the accordions, the folders within them, and the locations of your reports.
			</para>
			<note>
				<para>
					When you create your own report, the report is not automatically available. You must add it to a report menu.
				</para>
			</note>
			<para>
				The report menu is a hierarchical structure that consists of the following components:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Top Level</guilabel> under which the accordions are shown. (<guilabel>Top Level</guilabel> is only displayed when you are in the report menu editor.) 
						<remark>
							Reports menu editor? is that "Edit Report Menus"?
						</remark>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Accordions that are general categories for the reports. The defaults supplied are <guilabel>Configuration Management</guilabel>, <guilabel>Migration Readiness, Operations</guilabel>, <guilabel>VM Sprawl</guilabel>, <guilabel>Relationships</guilabel>, and <guilabel>Events</guilabel>. 
						<remark>
							What about Performance by Asset Type, Running Processes, Trending, Provisioning? are they defaults too?
						</remark>
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Folders that are used to further organize reports within an accordion. For example, under the <guilabel>Configuration Management</guilabel>, you would see folders for virtual machines, hosts, and other virtual infrastructure components.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Reports that are stored directly in the folders.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<xi:include href="topics/To_manage_Report_Menu_Accordions.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_manage_Report_Menu_Folders.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_organize_reports_in_Report_Menus.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Usage">
		<title>Usage</title> 
		<para>
			Usage provides a targeted view of CPU, RAM, disk space, disk I/O, and network I/O for tagged virtual machines. This allows you to find which virtual machines are using or overusing resources.
		</para>
		<para>
			There are two requirements to use this feature:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					You must assign tags to the virtual machines that you want to collect usage data for. See <xref linkend="To_tag_Virtual_Machines_and_Templates" />.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Capacity and utilization collection must be enabled. For more information on configuring capacity and utilization charts, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_CloudForms/3.1/html/Management_Engine_5.3_User_Guide/index.html">CloudForms Management Engine User Guide</ulink>.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_access_Usage_data.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Chargeback">
		<title>Chargeback</title> 
		<para>
			The chargeback feature allows you to calculate monetary virtual machine charges based on owner or company tag. To use this feature you must be collecting capacity and utilization data. For information on server control settings and capacity &amp; utilization collection settings, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_CloudForms/3.2/html/Settings_and_Operations_Guide/index.html">CloudForms Management Engine Settings and Operations Guide</ulink>.
		</para>
		<xi:include href="topics/Chargeback_Rates.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_chargeback_rates.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_assign_chargeback_rates.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_chargeback_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Timelines">
		<title>Timelines</title>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_access_and_use_a_Timeline.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_download_a_Timelines_data.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-RSS">
		<title>RSS</title>
		<xi:include href="topics/RSS.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
</chapter>