<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Defining_Policies_and_Profiles.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_create_a_Control_Policy" remap="TID_14730">
	<title>Creating Control Policies</title>
	<para>
		Create control policies by combining an event, a condition, and an action. Plan carefully the purpose of your policy before creating it. You can also use a scope expression that is tested immediately when the policy is triggered by an event. If the item is out of scope, then the policy does not continue on to the conditions, and none of the associated actions run.
	</para>
	<para>
		The procedure below describes how to create a control policy, its underlying conditions, and assign its events and actions in one process. Conditions and custom actions can be created separately as well. Those procedures are described in later sections in conditions and actions. Also, a description of all events is provided in events.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a Control Policy</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Control</guimenu><guisubmenu>Explorer</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guimenu>Policies</guimenu> accordion, and select <guilabel>Control Policies</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select either <guimenu>Host Control Policies</guimenu> or <guimenu>VM Control Policies</guimenu>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Add New Host/VM Control Policy</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Type in a <guilabel>Description</guilabel>.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1849.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Uncheck <guilabel>Active</guilabel> if you do not want this policy processed even when assigned to a resource.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				You can enter a <guilabel>Scope</guilabel> here (You can also create a scope as part of a condition, or not use one at all). If the host or virtual machine is not included in the scope, no actions will be run.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Notes</guilabel> area, add a detailed explanation of the policy.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>. You are brought to the page where you add conditions and events to your new policy.
			</para>
			<para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1850.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>) to associate conditions, events, and actions with the policy.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>