<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Detecting_Drift_on_Instances_or_Images" remap="TID_21651">
	<title>Detecting Drift on Instances or Images</title>
	<para>
		The configuration of an instance might change over time. <guilabel>Drift</guilabel> is the comparison of an instance to itself at different points in time. The instance need analysis at least twice to collect this information. Detecting drift provides you the following benefits:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				See the difference between the last known state of a machine and its current state
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Review the configuration changes that happen to a particular instance between multiple points in time.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Review the association changes that happen to a particular instance between multiple points in time.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Review the classification changes that happen to an instance between 2 time checks.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Capture the configuration drifts for a single instance across a time period.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<procedure>
		<title>To View Drift on an Instance Or Image</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Clouds</guimenu><guisubmenu>Instances</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the accordion for the item to view drift.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the item to view its <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> area in the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>, click <guibutton>Drift History</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the checkboxes for the analyses to compare.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1946.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Select up to 10 timestamps for Drift Analysis)</guibutton> at the top of the screen. The results display.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Check the <guilabel>Drift</guilabel> sections on the left to view in your comparison.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The following descriptions pertain to the <guilabel>Expanded View</guilabel>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/2023.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>. Whether you see the value of a property or an icon representing the property depends on the properties type.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A property displayed in the same color as the base means the compared analysis matches the base for that property.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A property displayed in a different color from the base means the compared analysis does not match the base for that property.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you are in the <guilabel>Compressed View</guilabel>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/2024.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>, the values of the properties are not displayed. All items are described by the icons shown below.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2150.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(checkmark)</guibutton> means that the compared analysis matches the base for that property. If you hover over it, the value of the property will display.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2177.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(triangle)</guibutton> means the compared analysis does not match the base for that property. If you hover over it, the value of the property displays. Click the minus sign next to the sections name to collapse it.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To limit the scope of the view, you have three buttons in the <guilabel>Resource</guilabel> button area.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2178.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(All attributes)</guibutton> to see all attributes of the sections you selected.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2204.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Attributes with different values)</guibutton> to see only the attributes that are different across the drifts.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2148.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Attributes with the same values)</guibutton> to see only the attributes that are the same across drifts.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To limit the mode of the view, there are two buttons in the <guilabel>Resource</guilabel> button area.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2022.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Details Mode)</guibutton> to see all details for an attribute.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2025.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Exists Mode)</guibutton> to only see if an attribute exists compared to the base or not. This only applies to attributes that can have a Boolean property. For example, a user account exists or does not exist, or a piece of hardware that does or does not exist.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			This creates a drift analysis. Download the data or create a report from your drift for analysis using external tools.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>