<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Lifecycle_and_Automation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Catalogs1" remap="TID_15574">
	<title>Catalogs</title>
	<para>
		Catalogs are used to create groups of virtual machines or instances for provisioning. For example, a complete package of a database server, desktop with specialized software already on it, and a firewall. You will need to complete the following steps to create and provision a service catalog.
	</para>
	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create <guilabel>Catalog Items</guilabel> for each virtual machine or instance that will be part of the service.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create a <guilabel>Service</guilabel> dialog. For example, create a dropdown with three options small, medium, and large.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create a method for the Service Dialog. This method defines what each of the options means to each of the individual virtual machines or cloud instances for the service. This method is called from a service provisioning instance in the Automate model.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create an instance in the DOMAIN/Service/Provisioning/StateMachines/ServiceProvision_Template class that calls the method.
			</para>
			<note>
				<para>
					DOMAIN must be a user-defined Domain and not the locked ManageIQ Domain. If necessary, you can copy the class from the ManageIQ domain into a custom domain.
				</para>
			</note>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Associate method with Automate instance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Create a <guilabel>Catalog Bundle</guilabel>, adding each of the catalog items to it. Select the <guilabel>Service Dialog</guilabel> you created. Use the instance created in the DOMAIN/Service/Provisioning/StateMachines/ServiceProvision_Template class as the <guilabel>Entry Point</guilabel>. Check <guilabel>Display in Catalog</guilabel> box.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Provision a service.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
</section>