<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Control_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Policies">
	<title>Policies</title> 
	<para>
		Policies are used to manage your virtual environment. There are two types of policies available: compliance and control. Compliance policies are used to harden your virtual infrastructure, making sure that your security requirements are adhered to. Control policies are used to check for a specific condition and perform an action based on the outcome. For example:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Prevent virtual machines from running without an administrator account.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Prevent virtual machines from starting if certain patches are not applied.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Configure the behavior of a production virtual machine to only start if it is running on a production host.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Force a SmartState Analysis when a host is added or removed from a cluster.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<section id="sect-Control_Policies">
		<title>Control Policies</title> 
		<para>
			A control policy is a combination of an event, a condition, and an action. This combination provides management capabilities in your virtual environment.
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					An event is a trigger to check a condition.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					A condition is a test triggered by an event.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					An action is an execution that occurs if a condition is met.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_Control_Policy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Editing_Basic_Info_Scope_and_Notes_for_a_Policy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Copying_a_Policy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Deleting_a_Policy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Creating_a_new_Policy_Condition.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Editing_Policy_Condition_Assignments.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Editing_Policy_Event_Assignments.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_assign_an_Action_to_an_Event.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Compliance_Policies">
		<title>Compliance Policies</title> 
		<para>
			Compliance policies are specifically designed to secure your environment by checking conditions that you create. These conditions can include the same conditions that you would use in a control policy, and most of the procedures are the same. However, a compliance policy automatically assigns the mark as a compliant action when the virtual machine or host passes all of the conditions. If any of the conditions are not met, then the virtual machine or host is marked as non-compliant. The compliance status is shown in the summary screen for the virtual machine or host and on the compare and drift screens.
		</para>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_compliance_Policy.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_create_a_Condition_to_check_file_contents_of_a_host.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<section id="sect-Checking_for_Compliance">
			<title>Checking for Compliance</title> 
			<para>
				After you have created your compliance policies and assigned them to a policy profile, you can check compliance in two ways. You can either schedule the compliance check or perform the check directly from the summary screen.
			</para>
			<para>
				The compliance check runs all compliance policies that are assigned to the host or virtual machine. If the item fails any of the checks, it is marked as non-compliant in the item's summary screen.
			</para>
			<note>
				<para>
					To schedule, you must have <literal>EvmRole-administrator</literal> access to the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server.
				</para>
			</note>
			<xi:include href="topics/To_schedule_a_Compliance_check.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_check_a_Virtual_Machine_for_Compliance_from_the_Summary_Screen.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
			<xi:include href="topics/To_check_a_Host_for_Compliance_from_the_Summary_Screen.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>