<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Account_Roles_and_Descriptions" remap="TID_15016">
	<title>Account Roles and Descriptions</title>
	<informaltable frame="all">
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Role
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Administrator
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Administrator of the virtual infrastructure. Can access all infrastructure functionality. Cannot change server configuration.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Approver
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Approver of processes, but not operations. Can view items in the virtual infrastructure, view all aspects of policies and assign policies to policy profiles. Cannot perform actions on infrastructure items.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Auditor
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Able to see virtual infrastructure for auditing purposes. Can view all infrastructure items. Cannot perform actions on them.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Desktop
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Access to VDI pages.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Operator
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Performs operations of virtual infrastructure. Can view and perform all functions on virtual infrastructure items including starting and stopping virtual machines. Cannot assign policy, but can view policy simulation from Virtual Machine page.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Security
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Enforces security for the virtual environment. Can assign policies to policy profiles, control user accounts, and view all parts of virtual infrastructure. Cannot create policies or perform actions on virtual infrastructure.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Super Administrator
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Administrator of <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> and the virtual infrastructure. Can access all functionality and configuration areas.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Support
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Access to features required by a support department such as diagnostics (logs). Can view all infrastructure items and logs. Cannot perform actions on them.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User of the virtual infrastructure. Can view all virtual infrastructure items. Cannot perform actions on them.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User Limited Self Service
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Limited User of virtual machines. Can make provision requests. Can access some functions on the virtual machine that the user owns including changing power state.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User Self Service
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User of virtual machines. Can make provision requests. Can access some functions on the virtual machine that the user owns and that the user's LDAP groups own including changing power state.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM User
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User of virtual machines. Can access all functions on the virtual machine including changing power state and viewing its console. Cannot assign policy, but can view policy simulation from virtual machine page.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>
</section>