<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Server_Roles" remap="TID_14969">
	<title>Server Roles</title>
	<para />
	<informaltable frame="all">
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Server Role
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Automation Engine
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Use this role if you want to use this <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server to process automation tasks.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Capacity and Utilization
						</para>
						<para>
							(3 Server Roles)
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<itemizedlist>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									The <guilabel>Capacity &amp; Utilization Coordinator</guilabel> role checks to see if it is time to collect data, somewhat like a scheduler. If it is time, a job is queued for the Capacity and Utilization Data Collector. The coordinator role is required to complete Capacity and Utilization data collection. If more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server in a specific zone has this role, only one will be active at a time.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									The <guilabel>Capacity &amp; Utilization Data Collector</guilabel> performs the actual collection of capacity and utilization data. This role has a dedicated worker, and there can be more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server with this role in a zone.
								</para>
							</listitem>
							<listitem>
								<para>
									The <guilabel>Capacity &amp; Utilization Data Processor</guilabel> processes all of the data collected, allowing <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> to create charts. This role has a dedicated worker, and there can be more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server with this role in a zone.
								</para>
							</listitem>
						</itemizedlist>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Database Operations
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Use Database Operations to enable this <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server to run database backups or garbage collection.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Database Synchronization
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Use <guilabel>Database Synchronization</guilabel> to enable this <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server's VMDB to replicate to a higher-level VMDB. This should only be enabled after creating settings for the Replication Worker.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Event Monitor
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default and provides the information shown in timelines. <guilabel>Event Monitor</guilabel> is responsible for the work between the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server and your providers. It starts 2 workers for each provider. One worker, the monitor, is responsible for maintaining a connection to a provider, catching events, and putting them on the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> message queue for processing. The second worker, the handler, is a message queue worker responsible for delivering only those messages for a provider. You should have at least one of these in each zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Notifier
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Use this role if you will be using <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Control or Automate to forward SNMP traps to a monitoring system or send e-mails. See <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/CloudForms/3.1/html/Management_Engine_5.3_Control_Guide/"><productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Control Guide</ulink> for details on creating SNMP alerts. If more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server in a specific zone has this role, only one will be active at a time.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Inventory
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. This role is responsible for refreshing provider information including EMS, hosts, virtual machines, and clusters, and is also responsible for capturing datastore file lists. If more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server in a specific zone has this role, only one will be active at a time.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Operations
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. This role sends stop, start, suspend, shutdown guest, clone, reconfigure, and unregister to the provider, directly from the console or through a policy action if you have <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Control. More than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server can have this role in a zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							RHN Mirror
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							An appliance with <guilabel>RHN Mirror</guilabel> enabled acts as a server containing a repository with the latest <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> packages. This also configures other Appliances within the same region to point to the chosen <guilabel>RHN Mirror</guilabel> server for updates. This provides a low bandwidth method to update environments with multiple Appliances.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Reporting
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. The <guilabel>Reporting</guilabel> role specifies which <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> servers can generate reports. If you do not have a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server set to this role in a zone, then no reports can be generated in that zone. You should have at least one of these in each zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Scheduler
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. The <guilabel>Scheduler</guilabel> sends messages to start all scheduled activities such as report generation and SmartState Analysis. This role also controls all system schedules such as capacity and utilization data gathering. One server in each zone must be assigned this role or scheduled <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> events will not occur. If more than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server in a specific zone has this role, only one will be active at a time.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							SmartProxy
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Enabling the <guilabel>SmartProxy</guilabel> role turns on the embedded SmartProxy on the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server. The embedded SmartProxy can analyze virtual machines that are registered to a Host and templates that are associated with a provider. To provide visibility to repositories, install the SmartProxy on a host from the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> console. This SmartProxy can also analyze virtual machines on the host on which it is installed.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							SmartState Analysis
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. The <guilabel>SmartState Analysis</guilabel> role controls which <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> servers can control SmartState Analyses and process the data from the analysis. You should have at least one of these in each zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							User Interface
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. Uncheck <guilabel>User Interface</guilabel> if you do <emphasis>not</emphasis> want users to be able to access this <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server using the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> console. For example, you may want to turn this off if the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server is strictly being used for capacity and utilization or reporting generation. More than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server can have this role in a zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Web Services
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							This role is enabled by default. Uncheck <guilabel>Web Services</guilabel> to stop this <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server from acting as a Web service provider. More than one <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server can have this role in a zone.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>
	<para />
</section>