<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_enter_credentials_and_operating_system_for_the_target_Host" remap="TID_15077">
	<title>Entering Credentials and Operating System for the Target Host</title>
	<para>
		Set the credentials and operating system for the target host to prepare for the installation of SmartProxy.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Enter Credentials and Operating System for the Target Host</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Hosts</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Check the host you want to edit.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), then 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1851.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Edit Selected Hosts</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Credentials</guilabel> box, click the <guibutton>Default</guibutton> tab and enter your login credentials. If you are using domain credentials, the format for <guilabel>User ID</guilabel> must be in the format of <replaceable>&lt;domainname&gt;\&lt;username&gt;</replaceable>. For ESX hosts, if SSH login is disabled for the default user, click the <guibutton>Remote Login</guibutton> tab and enter a user with remote login access.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2112.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<important>
				<para>
					If the target is a Windows host, disconnect all network connections between the Windows proxy and the target. If an existing connection uses a different set of credentials than those set in the console, the installation may fail.
				</para>
			</important>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Validate</guibutton> to verify the credentials.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you added the host manually instead of <guilabel>Host Discovery</guilabel> or <guilabel>Provider Refresh</guilabel> finding it, select the host's operating system from the <guilabel>Host Platform</guilabel> drop-down box to ensure the host platform is available.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		When remotely installing on Windows hosts, the SmartProxy file is first copied to a Windows proxy. That computer then installs the file to the target host. The Windows proxy is the same as when you select the <guilabel>Default Repository SmartProxy</guilabel> box located by navigating to <menuchoice><guimenu>Configure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Configuration</guisubmenu></menuchoice>, then clicking on the desired server, then the <guimenu>Server</guimenu> tab, and exploring the <guimenu>Server Control</guimenu> area.
	</para>
</section>