<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_schedule_a_SmartState_Analysis_or_Compliance_Check" remap="TID_15002">
	<title>Scheduling a SmartState Analysis or Compliance Check</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Schedule a SmartState Analysis or Compliance Check</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guisubmenu>Configure</guisubmenu><guisubmenu>Configuration</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guilabel>Settings</guilabel> accordion, then click <guilabel>Schedules</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), and 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/plus_green.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Add a new Schedule</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Basic Information</guilabel> area, type in a <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel> for the schedule.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select <guilabel>Active</guilabel> to enable this scan.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Action</guilabel> list, select the type of analysis to schedule. Based on the type of analysis you choose, you are presented with one of the following group boxes.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2079.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>VM Analysis</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>VM Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All VMs</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Cluster</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Host</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single VM</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>Template Analysis</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>Template Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All Templates</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Templates for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Templates for Cluster</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Templates for Host</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single Template</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>Host Analysis</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>Host Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All Hosts</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Hosts for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single Host</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							You can only schedule host analyses for connected virtual machines, not repository virtual machines that were discovered through that host. Since repository virtual machines do not retain a relationship with the host that discovered them, there is no current way to scan them through the scheduling feature. The host is shown because it may have connected virtual machines in the future when the schedule is set to run.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>Cluster Analysis</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>Cluster Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All Clusters</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Clusters for Provider</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>A single Cluster</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>Datastore Analysis</guimenuitem>: Displays <guimenuitem>Datastore Selection</guimenuitem> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All Datastores</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Datastores for Host</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Datastores for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single Datastore</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>VM Compliance Check</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>VM Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All VMs</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Cluster</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All VMs for Host</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single VM</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<guimenuitem>Host Compliance Check</guimenuitem>: Displays <guilabel>Host Selection</guilabel> where you can choose to analyze <guimenuitem>All Hosts</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Hosts for Provider</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>All Hosts for Cluster</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>A single Host</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				By applying <guimenuitem>Global Filters</guimenuitem> within any of the above items, you can designate which virtual machines or hosts to analyze.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Timer</guilabel> area, click the <guilabel>Run</guilabel> list to set the frequency of the analysis to run. There are further options based on which <guilabel>Run</guilabel> option you choose.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2080.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Once</guimenuitem> to have the analysis run only one time.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Daily</guimenuitem> to run the analysis on a daily basis. You will be prompted to select the number of days between each analysis.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Hourly</guimenuitem> to run the analysis hourly. You will be prompted to select the number of hours between each analysis.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select a <guilabel>Time Zone</guilabel>. Note that if you change the <guilabel>Time Zone</guilabel>, you will need to reset the stating date and time.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Type or select a date to begin the schedule in <guilabel>Starting Date</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select a <guilabel>Starting Time</guilabel> based on a 24 hour clock in the selected <guilabel>Time Zone</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>
