<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="VMware_Console_Settings" remap="TID_14970">
	<title>VMware Console Settings</title>
	<para>
		If you are using the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Control feature set, then you have the ability to connect to a Web console for virtual machines that are registered to a host. To use this feature, you must have VNC installed, the appropriate version of the VMware MKS plug-in or the appropriate VMRC viewer installed in your Web browser. Note that you are responsible for installing the correct version for your virtual infrastructure. See vendors documentation for information.
	</para>
	<para>
		After installing the appropriate software or version, you must specify which version you are using in the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> configuration settings.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			To edit the <guimenuitem>VMware MKS plug-in</guimenuitem> settings, you must have the super administrator role.
		</para>
	</note>
	<para />
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2061.png" />
		</imageobject>
	</mediaobject>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				If you select <guimenuitem>VNC</guimenuitem>, type in the port number used. This port must be open on the target virtual machine and the VNC software must be installed there. On the computer that you are running the console from, you must install the appropriate version of <application>Java Runtime</application> if it is not already installed.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				If you select <guimenuitem>VMware MKS plug-in</guimenuitem>, select the appropriate version.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				If using <guimenuitem>VMware VMRC plug-in</guimenuitem>, be sure that you have fulfilled the requirements.
			</para>
			<para>
				The correct version of the VMRC plug-in from VMware must be installed on the client computer. To do this, log into the Virtual Center Web Service and attempt to open a virtual machine console. This should prompt you to install the required plug-in.
			</para>
			<para>
				The VSphere Web Client must be installed on VC version 5, and the provider must be registered to it. For Virtual Center version 4, the VMware VirtualCenter Management Webservice must be running.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>