<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Lifecycle_and_Automation_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Requirements_for_Provisioning_Virtual_Machines_from_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization_Managers1" remap="TID_15506">
	<title>Requirements for Provisioning Virtual Machines from Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</title>
	<informaltable frame="all">
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Item
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Requirements
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</productname> version 3.0 or higher
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</productname> properly installed with API in default location <uri>(https://server:8443/api)</uri>.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</productname> History Database
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</productname> Data Warehouse (DWH) properly installed with access to the PostgreSQL database on the <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager</productname> server.
						</para>
						<para>
							Port 5432 open in iptables.
						</para>
						<para>
							md5 authentication allowed to <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliances in <filename>pg_hba.conf</filename>.
						</para>
						<para>
							PostgreSQL set to listen for connections on <literal>*:5432</literal> in <filename>postgresql.conf</filename>.
						</para>
						<para>
							Credentials provided during database setup to be used in <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> UI.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Storage Supported for <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Virtual Machine Analysis
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							NFS - <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> server must be able to mount NFS storage domain.
						</para>
						<para>
							iSCSI / FCP - Cluster must use full <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux</productname> (not Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Hypervisor) Hosts.
						</para>
						<para>
							DirectLUN Hook installed on each host and registered to <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Managers</productname>.
						</para>
						<para>
							Must have <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance in each Cluster with this storage type.
						</para>
						<para> 
							<productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> appliance virtual machine container must have DirectLUN attribute set.
						</para>
						<para>
							Local storage - Not yet supported (Red Hat does not recommend due to single point of failure).
						</para>
						<para />
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</informaltable>
	<para />
</section>