<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Integration_with_AWS_CloudFormation_and_OpenStack_Heat.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Ordering_Service" remap="TID_44362">
	<title>Ordering Service</title>
	<para>
		Use this procedure to order a service catalog item using the dashboard UI.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Services</guimenu><guisubmenu>Catalog</guisubmenu></menuchoice> and select <guimenu>Service Catalogs</guimenu> in the accordion menu.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guisubmenu>All Services</guisubmenu> catalogs, select the catalog item that you want to order. The <guilabel>Service</guilabel> window with the name and description of the service to be ordered is displayed.
			</para>
			<mediaobject> 
				<!--<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/7152.png" />
				</imageobject>-->
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/7172.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Order</guibutton>. The <guilabel>Order Service</guilabel> window with <guilabel>Options</guilabel> and <guilabel>Parameter</guilabel> is displayed.
			</para>
			<mediaobject> 
				<!--<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/7157.png" />
				</imageobject>-->
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/7173.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter stack name in <guimenu>Stack Name</guimenu>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>On Failure</guilabel> value is <literal>Rollback</literal> by default.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Timeout</guilabel> is optional. You can type the number of seconds to timeout the provision at the provider side. Note that the number of seconds get converted (rounded) to minutes when ordering the provision through OpenStack. For example, 100 seconds rounds to two minutes.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				You can use the default parameter values from the template, or enter new values as appropriate. Note that the <guilabel>Parameters</guilabel> vary per dialog; therefore, the parameters shown in the above screenshot may or may not exist depending on the dialog.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Submit</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The order request is submitted. After a request has been approved, the various stages of fulfillment are executed. You can see the progress status of the provisioning process in <menuchoice><guimenu>Services</guimenu><guisubmenu>Requests</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
	</para>
</section>