<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Control_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Events">
	<title>Events</title> 
	<para>
		Events are triggers that cause a condition to be tested. <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Control provides several Events, that can be divided into functional types. Events cannot be modified.
	</para> 
	<!--para>
		Table: Event Types
	</para-->
	<table frame="all">
		<title>Event Types</title>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Category
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Datastore Operation
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events related to datastore analysis.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Authentication Validation
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events related to credential validation for hosts and providers.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Company Tag
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events related to assigning and removing company tags from an infrastructure object.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Compliance
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events related to checking compliance policies.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Operation
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events related to the connection state of a host and status of a SmartState Analysis on a host.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Configuration
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events associated with a change in configuration of a virtual machine. These include, but are not limited to, clone, create, template create, and settings change.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Lifecycle
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events such as virtual machine discovery, provisioning, and virtual machine retirement.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Operation
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events associated with power states or locations of virtual machines and virtual desktop machines. These include, but are not limited to, power off, power on, reset, resume, shutdown, and suspend.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Service Lifecycle
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Events associated with service lifecycle. These include, but are not limited to, provisioning completed, start request, started, stop request, stopped, retirement warning, and retired.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table> 
	<!--para/-->
	<para>
		Each type has a set of events that you can select to trigger the checking of a condition.
	</para> 
	<!--para>
		Table: Events and Descriptions
	</para-->
	<table frame="all">
		<title>Events and Descriptions</title>
		<tgroup cols="2">
			<thead>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Event
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Description
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</thead>
			<tbody>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Datastore Analysis Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis of datastore completes.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Datastore Analysis Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis for a datastore is requested from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Added to Cluster
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host is added to a cluster.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Analysis Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis of host completes.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Analysis Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis is requested from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Changed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when host authentication credentials are changed in the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Error
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition if there is any other error connecting to the host such as ssh/vim handshaking problems, timeouts, or any other uncategorized error.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Incomplete Credentials
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition if host authentication credentials are not complete in the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Invalid
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition if CloudForms Management Engine is able to communicate with the host and the credentials fail.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Unreachable
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition if CloudForms Management Engine is unable to communicate with the host.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Auth Valid
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the host authentication credentials entered in the CloudForms Management Engine console are valid.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host C &amp; U Processing Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the processing of capacity and utilization data has finished.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Compliance Check
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a compliance check is performed on a host.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Compliance Failed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host fails a compliance check.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Compliance Passed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host passes a compliance check.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Connect
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host connects to a provider.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Disconnect
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host disconnects from a provider.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Host Removed from Cluster
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a host is removed from a cluster.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Changed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition when provider authentication credentials are changed in the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Error
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition if there is any other error connecting to the provider such as ssh/vim handshaking problems, timeouts, or any other uncategorized error.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Incomplete Credentials
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition if provider authentication credentials are not complete in the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Invalid
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition if CloudForms Management Engine is able to communicate with the provider and the credentials fail.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Unreachable
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition if CloudForms Management Engine is unable to communicate with the provider.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Provider Auth Valid
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para> 
							<emphasis>For use only with CloudForms Management Engine automate, for future use in policies.</emphasis> Check the condition when the provider authentication credentials entered in the CloudForms Management Engine console are valid.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Provision Complete
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service provision is complete.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Retired
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service has been retired.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Retirement Warning
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service is about to retire.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Start Request
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service has been requested to start.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Started
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service has started.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Stop Request
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service has been requested to stop.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						Service Stopped
					</entry>
					<entry>
						Check the condition when the service has stopped.
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is assigned.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Parent Cluster Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is assigned to a virtual machine's parent cluster.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Parent Datastore Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is assigned to a virtual machine's parent datastore.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Parent Host Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is assigned to a virtual machine's parent host.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Parent Resource Pool Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is assigned to a virtual machine's parent resource pool.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Tag Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when assignment of a company tag is attempted.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a company tag is removed.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Parent Cluster Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is removed from a virtual machine's parent cluster.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Parent Datastore Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is removed from a virtual machine's parent datastore.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Parent Host Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is removed from a virtual machine's parent host.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Parent Resource Pool Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition after a company tag is removed from a virtual machine's parent resource pool.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Un-Tag Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when an attempt is made to remove a company tag.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VDI Connecting to Session
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a VDI session is started.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VDI Disconnected from Session
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a VDI session is disconnected.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VDI Login Session
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a user logs on to a VDI session.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VDI Logoff Session
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a user logs off from a VDI session.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Analysis Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis of virtual machine completes.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Analysis Failure
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis of virtual machine fails.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Analysis Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis is requested from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Analysis Start
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a SmartState Analysis of virtual machine is started.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM C &amp; U Processing Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the processing of capacity and utilization data has finished.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Clone Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is cloned.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Clone Start
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine clone is started.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Compliance Check
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a compliance check is performed on a virtual machine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Compliance Failed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine fails a compliance check.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Compliance Passed
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine passes a compliance check.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Create Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is created.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Delete (from Disk) Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to delete a virtual machine from disk from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Discovery
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when CloudForms Management Engine discovers a virtual machine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Guest Reboot
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is rebooted.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Guest Reboot Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to reboot a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Guest Shutdown
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the operating system of a virtual machine shuts down.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Guest Shutdown Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to shut down the operating system of a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Live Migration (VMOTION)
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a VMOTION is performed.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Power Off
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is turned off.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Power Off Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to power off a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Power On
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is turned on.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Power On Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to turn on a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Provision Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is provisioned.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Remote Console Connected
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is connected to a remote console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Removal from Inventory
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is unregistered.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Removal from Inventory Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a request is sent from the CloudForms Management Engine console to unregister a virtual machine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Renamed Event
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is renamed on its provider.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Reset
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is restarted.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Reset Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is restarted from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Retire Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine retirement request is created from CloudForms Management Engine.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Retired
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is retired.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Retirement Warning
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a warning threshold is reached for retirement.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Settings Change
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the settings of virtual machine are changed.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Snapshot Create Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a snapshot is completed.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Snapshot Create Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to create a snapshot of a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Snapshot Create Started
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a snapshot creation is started.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Standby of Guest
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when the operating system of a virtual machine goes to standby.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Standby of Guest Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to put the operating system of a virtual machine in standby from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Suspend
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine is suspended.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Suspend Request
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when someone tries to suspend a virtual machine from the CloudForms Management Engine console.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
				<row>
					<entry>
						<para>
							VM Template Create Complete
						</para>
					</entry>
					<entry>
						<para>
							Check the condition when a virtual machine template is created.
						</para>
					</entry>
				</row>
			</tbody>
		</tgroup>
	</table>
</chapter>