<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Known_Issue" remap="TID_44382">
	<title>Known Issue</title>
	<para>
		These known issues exist in Red Hat CloudForms at this time:
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1209711">1209711</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The previous version of CloudForms Management Engine collected inventory on all snapshots for Red Hat OpenStack Platform causing significant EmsRefresh slowdown. This issue was being caused due to scalability issue in the refresh process that could not handle large volumes of OpenStack Platform cinder snapshots. A temporary workaround has been provided to fix this issue until the underlying scalability problem can be fixed. The fix will allow users that have large volumes of snapshots to disable collection of snapshots, to avoid the EmsRefresh slowdown.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1212087">1212087</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					CloudForms Management Engine supports connecting to OpenStack APIs over SSL. However, it requires that the Keystone service API be configured to use SSL and that Red Hat CloudForms be configured to use the Keystone SSL port. If Red Hat CloudForms does not connect to Keystone over SSL, it will fail to connect to other OpenStack services that are configured to use SSL.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1222591">1222591</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					In Red Hat CloudForms 3.2 (CloudForms Management Engine 5.4), the cloud-init function blocks SSH access for the root user to virtual machines hosted in Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.4 environments. Note that this issue only occurs in Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.4, and that cloud-init functions correctly for Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.3 and Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization 3.5. This issue will be addressed in a future release.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1222958">1222958</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When an OpenStack provider is set up with services behind SSL termination, and a Red Hat CloudForms appliance is configured to communicate to the Keystone SSL endpoint, users may see the following error in the evm.log (and fog.log):
				</para>
				<para>
					#&lt;Excon::Errors::SocketError: end of file reached (EOFError)&gt;
				</para>
				<para>
					This error occurs because Red Hat CloudForms tries both non-SSL and SSL connections when getting the Keystone security token. This is a benign known issue and is scheduled to be addressed in a future version.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1223324">1223324</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					In Red Hat CloudForms 3.2, the oo-install-ose command used to set up OpenShift on Red Hat CloudForms fails because the incorrect version of Ruby is installed. As a workaround, perform the following procedure:
				</para>
				<procedure>
					<step>
						<para>
							Download and unpack oo-install-ose:
						</para>
						<screen># cd /root
# wget -O oo-install-ose.tgz &lt;the link from [2]&gt;
# tar xfv oo-install-ose.tgz
# mv oo-install oo-install-ose</screen>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							Install SCL Ruby:
						</para>
						<screen># subscription-manager repos --enable rhel-server-rhscl-6-rpms
# yum install ruby193-ruby-irb ruby193-ruby</screen>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							Verify that Ruby has been installed:
						</para>
						<screen># scl enable ruby193 "ruby -v"</screen>
					</step>
					<step>
						<para>
							Create a shim that runs the oo-install-ose in ruby193 scl
						</para>
						<screen># cd oo-install-ose
# mv oo-install-ose oo-install-ose-orig
# vim oo-install-ose:

--------------------------------------------------
#!/usr/bin/env bash

scl enable ruby193 "./oo-install-ose-orig $@"
chmod +x oo-install-ose
--------------------------------------------------
</screen>
					</step>
				</procedure>
				<para>
					This issue will be resolved in a future release of Red Hat CloudForms.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1225541">1225541</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					At current, attempting to perform a Smart State analysis of a VMware vSphere 6 virtual machine with Virtual Disk Development Kit 6.0 returns an 'Unable to determine port' error, causing the analysis to fail. As a workaround, use Virtual Disk Development Kit 5.5. This issue will be resolved in a future release of Red Hat CloudForms.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>