<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Release_Notes" remap="TID_44381">
	<title>Release Notes</title>
	<para>
		This section outlines important details about the release, including recommended practices and notable changes to Red Hat CloudForms. You must take this information into account to ensure the best possible outcomes for your deployment.
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1044597">1044597</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The new version of CloudForms Management Engine now allows Red Hat Enterprise Linux OpenStack Platform events use in policies. Previously Red Hat Enterprise Linux OpenStack Platform events could only be captured in either the policy log or by alerts.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1169937">1169937</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					This enhancement adds support for using the Subscription Asset Manager (SAM) Account Name as an alternative to the user principal name when authenticating against Active Directory. This enables users to use their SAM account name in environments, using the SAM account name in place of the user's principal name for authentication.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>BZ#<ulink url="https://bugzilla.redhat.com/1212123">1212123</ulink></term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					In the current version of CloudForms Management Engine, the operating system part of the QuadIcon for virtual machines hosted on an OpenStack provider is unknown and shown as a question mark. The operating system icon is displayed correctly after smart state analysis has been performed on the instance or virtual machine image.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>