<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_create_a_Time_Profile" remap="TID_14921">
	<title>Creating a Time Profile</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a Time Profile</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guisubmenu>Configure</guisubmenu><guisubmenu>My Settings</guisubmenu></menuchoice>, then click on the <guilabel>Time Profiles</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), and 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/plus_green.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Add a new Time Profile</guilabel>).
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2039.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Type a meaningful name in the <guilabel>Description</guilabel> field.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				For <guilabel>Scope</guilabel>, select <guimenuitem>All Users</guimenuitem> to create a global time profile available to all users. Only the super administration and administration roles can create, edit, and delete a global profile. Select <guimenuitem>Current User</guimenuitem> if this time profile should only be available to the user creating it.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Check the <guilabel>Days</guilabel> and <guilabel>Hours</guilabel> for the time profile.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				For <guilabel>Timezone</guilabel>, you can select a specific time zone or, you can let the user select a time zone when displaying data.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you select a specific time zone, you also have the option to <guilabel>Roll Up Daily Performance</guilabel> data. This option is only available to users with the administration or super administration role. Enabling the <guilabel>Roll Up Daily Performance</guilabel> option reduces the time required to process daily capacity and utilization reports and to display daily capacity and utilization charts.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<note>
		<para>
			The following relationships exist between time zones and performance reports: 
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The configured time zone in a performance report is used to select rolled up performance data, regardless of the user's selected time zone.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If the configured time zone is null, it defaults to UTC time for performance reports.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If there is no time profile with the report's configured time zone that is also set to roll up capacity and utilization data, the report does not find any records.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
		<para>
			For non-performance reports, the user's time zone is used when displaying dates and times in report rows.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>
