<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Settings_and_Operations_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_create_a_tag_category" remap="TID_14940">
	<title>Creating a Tag Category</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a Tag Category</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guisubmenu>Configure</guisubmenu><guisubmenu>Configuration</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on the <guilabel>Settings</guilabel> accordion, then <guilabel>Region</guilabel>, then click on the <guilabel>My Company Categories</guilabel> tab.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Click to add a new category</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Category Information</guilabel> area,
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2042.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Name</guilabel> to create a short name that refers to category in the VMDB.
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Single Value</guilabel> fields cannot be changed after the category has been added.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Display Name</guilabel> to specify how you want to see the name of the category in the Console.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Description</guilabel> to type a brief explanation of how the category should be used. This shows when you try to add a value to the category.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <guilabel>Show in Console</guilabel> when you feel that the category is ready for use in the console. For example, you want to populate values for the category before exposing it to users.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <guilabel>Single Value</guilabel> for categories that can only have a single value assigned to a resource. For example, a virtual machine can only be assigned to one location, but could belong to more than one department.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <guilabel>Capture C &amp; U Data</guilabel> by tag to be able to group capacity and utilization data by this tag category. To use this, be sure to assign this tag to all the resources that you want to group by.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			Repeat these steps for each category you need. After you have created the category, you can add values to it.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<important>
		<para>
			If no values are created for a category, you are unable to assign a value from that category nor be able to filter by that category.
		</para>
	</important>
</section>