<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Installing_CloudForms_on_VMware_vSphere.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Advanced_Configuration_Settings" remap="TID_31339">
	<title>Advanced Configuration Settings</title>
	<para>
		After logging in you can use the following menu items for advanced configuration of the appliance:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Set DHCP Network Configuration</guilabel> to use DHCP to obtain the IP address and network configuration for your <productname>CloudForms Management Engine Appliance</productname>. The appliance is initially configured as a DHCP client with bridged networking.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Set Static Network Configuration</guilabel> if you have a specific IP address and network settings you need to use for the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine Appliance</productname>.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Test Network Configuration</guilabel> to check that name resolution is working correctly.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Set Hostname</guilabel> to specify a hostname for the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Set Timezone, Date, and Time</guilabel> to configure the time zone, date, and time for the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Disable PostgreSQL Database Server</guilabel> if you know that you will be using another database server and do not want these additional services loaded. This option will disable <application>PostgreSQL</application> and unmount the disk associated with the database. The <productname>CloudForms Management Engine Appliance</productname> will need a restart.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Restore Factory Configuration</guilabel> to overwrite any changes you have made to the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance, restore the factory configuration, add the <application>PostgreSQL</application> service, and restart the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance. Note that this does not set the Appliance to use the internal PostgreSQL database.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Restore Database from Backup</guilabel> to restore the VMDB database from a previous backup.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Setup Database Region</guilabel> to create regions for VMDB replication.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Configure Database</guilabel> to configure the VMDB database. Use this option to configure the database for the appliance after installing and running it for the first time.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Stop Server Processes</guilabel> to stop all server processes. You may need to do this to perform maintenance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Start Server Processes</guilabel> to start the server. You may need to do this after performing maintenance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Restart Appliance</guilabel> to restart the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance. You can either restart the appliance and clear the logs or just restart the appliance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Shut Down Appliance</guilabel> to power down the appliance and exit all processes.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Summary Information</guilabel> to go back to the network summary screen for the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine Appliance</productname>.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Log Off</guilabel> to log out of the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance console.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>