<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Deployment_Planning_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Architecture2" remap="TID_14720">
	<title>Architecture</title>
	<para>
		The diagram below describes the capabilities of CloudForms Management Engine. Its features are designed to work together to provide robust management and maintenance of your virtual infrastructure.
	</para>
	<figure>
		<title>Features</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1845.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<para>
		The architecture comprises the following components:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The CloudForms Management Engine Appliance (Appliance) which is supplied as a secure, high-performance, preconfigured virtual machine. It provides support for HTTPS communications.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The CloudForms Management Engine Server (Server) resides on the Appliance. It is the software layer that communicates between the SmartProxy and the Virtual Management Database. It includes support for HTTPS communications.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The Virtual Management Database (VMDB) resides either on the Appliance or another computer accessible to the Appliance. It is the definitive source of intelligence collected about your Virtual Infrastructure. It also holds status information regarding Appliance tasks.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The CloudForms Management Engine Console (Console) is the Web interface used to view and control the Server and Appliance. It is consumed through Web 2.0 mash-ups and web services (WS Management) interfaces.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The SmartProxy can reside on the Appliance or on an ESX Server. If not embedded in the Server, the SmartProxy can be deployed from the Appliance. Each storage location must have a SmartProxy with visibility to it. The SmartProxy acts on behalf of the Appliance communicating with it over HTTPS on standard port 443.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>