<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_plan_where_to_put_a_new_Virtual_Machine" remap="TID_15421">
	<title>Planning Where to Put a New Virtual Machine</title>
	<para>
		Use the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> planning feature to help you plan for a virtual machine placement.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Plan Where To Put a New Virtual Machine</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Optimize</guimenu><guisubmenu>Planning</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Reference VM Selection</guilabel>, use the dropdowns to select the virtual machine that is most like the one that you want to add.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2254.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the required <guilabel>VM Options</guilabel>, for what you want to base the calculations on.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2255.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Source</guilabel> dropdown, select the type of data to use as the source for your projections. For example, select <guimenuitem>Allocation</guimenuitem> to calculate based on the current allocation values of each resource (CPU, memory, or disk space) for the reference virtual machine. Use <guimenuitem>Reservation</guimenuitem> if you want to project based on the current guaranteed value of the specific resource (CPU Speed, CPU count, memory, or disk space) although that amount may not be allocated to the virtual machine at a specific moment in time. Select <guimenuitem>Usage</guimenuitem> if you want to calculate based on usage history of the reference virtual machine. Use <guilabel>Manual Input</guilabel>, to enter your own set of parameters for each resource.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Target Options</guilabel>, select if you want to use clusters or hosts as your targets.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2256.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<para>
				Also, select the limit of how high the projection can go for CPU, memory, and datastore space. If you are targeting hosts, you will be able to select a filter for which hosts can be targets.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Trend Options</guilabel>, select how far back you want to use the trend data for, a <guilabel>Time Profile</guilabel> and <guilabel>Time Zone</guilabel> if applicable. Note that <guilabel>Time Profile</guilabel> will only show if the logged on user has a Time Profile available.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Submit</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			The <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> tab shows the best clusters or hosts on which to place the virtual machines. The <guilabel>Report</guilabel> tab shows the best fit and statistics on the reference virtual machine in a tabular format. From the <guilabel>Report</guilabel> tab, you can also create a PDF of the report or download the data in txt or csv format.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>