<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Clouds">
	<title>Clouds</title> 
	<para>
		Cloud computing provides a set of pooled resources used to create a set of scalable virtual machine instances. Resources includes CPUs, memory, storage, and networking. While users of virtualization infrastructure environments provision whole virtual machines, users of cloud computing environments provision only the necessary resources to build their instances. This means the customer can easily scale their instances by provisioning more resources. Metric usage is focused on the hardware layer, and results in the user paying only the necessary resources.
	</para>
	<para>
		For example, a user might use an instance to store a web server. During peak times of use, the user provisions more cloud resources to maintain the performance of the server. During quiet times, the user reduces the consumption of cloud resources. As a result, the user only uses and pays for the resources used.
	</para>
	<para>
		CloudForms Management Engine offers a set of tools for viewing and maintaining cloud providers and their associated resources. Supported cloud providers include:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<application>Amazon EC2 (public cloud)</application>: is a central part of Amazon.com's cloud computing platform that allows users to rent virtual computers on which to run their own computer applications. It allows scalable deployment of applications by providing a Web service through which a user can boot an Amazon Machine Image to create a virtual machine, which Amazon calls an "instance", containing any software desired.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<application>OpenStack (private cloud)</application>: <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux OpenStack</productname> Platform provides the foundation to build a private or public Infrastructure-as-a-Service (IaaS) cloud on top of <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux</productname>. It offers a massively scalable, fault-tolerant platform for the development of cloud-enabled workloads. To learn more about OpenStack, see <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Linux_OpenStack_Platform/">Red Hat Enterprise Linux OpenStack Platform</ulink>, Getting Started category.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	</chapter>

