<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_schedule_a_Report" remap="TID_15447">
	<title>Scheduling a Report</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Schedule a Report</title>
		<para>
			You can view historical data by creating reports on a scheduled basis. In addition, scheduled reports can be emailed directly to users.
		</para>
		<step>
			<para>
				There are two ways to schedule a report. Select a report from the Reports accordion and click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>, 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guilabel>Add a New Schedule</guilabel>, or click the Schedules accordion and click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>, 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guilabel>Add a New Schedule</guilabel>.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2277.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In the <guilabel>Basic Information</guilabel> area, type in a <guilabel>Name</guilabel> and <guilabel>Description</guilabel> for the schedule.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						By default. <guilabel>Active</guilabel> is checked to enable the scan.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <guilabel>E-Mail after Running</guilabel> to send an email after the report has been generated. The email will be sent to the users email address as show in the <guilabel>Accounts</guilabel> area in <guimenu>Configuration</guimenu>. The email will include a link to the report. See <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_CloudForms/3.2/html/Settings_and_Operations_Guide/index.html">CloudForms Management Engine Settings and Operations Guide</ulink> to learn how to verify the address, and to validate outgoing email settings.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Report Selection</guilabel> area is pre-populated if you added the schedule directly from the report. If you are adding from the schedule according, use the <guilabel>Filter</guilabel> drop downs to select the report that you want to schedule.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2278.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Timer</guilabel> area, click the <guilabel>Run</guilabel> drop down to specify how often you want the analysis to run. Your options after that will depend on which run option you choose.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2279.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Once</guimenuitem> to have the analysis run just one time.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Daily</guimenuitem> to run the analysis on a daily basis. You will be prompted to select how many days you want between each analysis.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guimenuitem>Hourly</guimenuitem> to run the analysis hourly. You will be prompted to select how many hours you want between each analysis.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Type or select a date to begin the schedule in <guilabel>Starting Date</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Select a <guilabel>Starting Time</guilabel> based on a 24 hour clock in the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliances Time Zone.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						To send an email that includes an attachment with the report contents, check <guimenu>Send an E-mail</guimenu>. Parameters required for sending an email are displayed.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2281.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						In <guilabel>From (leave blank for default)</guilabel>, type in the sending email.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Add a User</guilabel>, to select a specific user. The user must have a valid email address entered under accounts.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Add (enter manually)</guilabel> to type in the address not registered to a User. Then, click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Add)</guibutton>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you are sending an email after the report runs, then you can select further options under Email Options.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2283.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <guilabel>Send if Report is Empty</guilabel> if you want an email even if no records exist in the report.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Next to Attachments, check if you would like the report attached as a <guimenuitem>Text</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>CSV</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>PDF</guimenuitem> file.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<note>
		<para>
			You may need to disable, change the report filter, or change the frequency of a schedule. To do this, you will need to edit the schedule.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>