<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_use_Comparison_Sections" remap="TID_15136">
	<title>Using the Virtual Machine Comparison Sections</title>
	<para>
		Use the comparison sections to view various comparison data and display the data in different ways.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Use Comparison Sections</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				On the left of a comparison screen, select what categories of properties to display.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Apply</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the plus sign next to the sections name to expand it.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The following descriptions pertain to the <guilabel>Expanded View</guilabel>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/2023.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>. Whether you see the value of a property or an icon representing the property depends on the properties type.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A property displayed in the same color as the base means that the compared virtual machine matches the base for that property.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A property displayed in a different color from the base means that the compared virtual machine does not match the base for that property.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you are in the <guilabel>Compressed View</guilabel>
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/2024.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject>, the values of the properties will not be displayed. The icons shown below will describe all items.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2150.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(checkmark)</guibutton> means that the compared virtual machine matches the base for that property. If you hover over it, the value of the property will display.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2151.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(x)</guibutton> means that the compared virtual machine does not match the base for that property. If you hover over it, the value of the property will display.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the minus sign next to the sections name to collapse it.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			Your comparison can be viewed in multiple ways. Export the data or create a report from your comparison for analysis using external tools.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>