<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Installing_CloudForms_on_Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Running_CloudForms_Management_Engine" remap="TID_18257">
	<title>Running CloudForms Management Engine</title>
	<para>
		After uploading the appliance to the export storage domain, import it as a template and create a virtual machine. Use the following procedure as a guide.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create and Run CloudForms Management Engine</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Import the appliance image from the export storage domain as a template in a Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization data storage domain. Use your chosen <replaceable>newimagename</replaceable> from <xref linkend="Uploading_the_CloudForms_Management_Engine_Appliance_with_the_Image_Uploader" /> to find the image to import as a template. See the section on <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization/3.4/html/Administration_Guide/sect-Importing_Templates.html">Importing Templates</ulink> in the <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization/3.4/html/Administration_Guide/">Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Administrator Guide</ulink> for instructions.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Once the import is complete, check the template for a network interface (NIC). If the template does not include one, create a NIC for it.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Create a new virtual machine using the CloudForms Management Engine Appliance template as a basis. See the <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com/documentation/en-US/Red_Hat_Enterprise_Virtualization/3.4/html/Administration_Guide/">Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Administrator Guide</ulink> for instructions.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Add a database disk if you are hosting the database on the same machine as the appliance.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Start the newly created CloudForms Management Engine Appliance virtual machine.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			Your Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization environment now contains a running CloudForms Management Engine Appliance.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>