<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Control_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Creating_a_new_Policy_Condition" remap="TID_14735">
	<title>Creating a New Policy Condition</title>
	<para>
		If you have not already created a condition to use with this policy, you can create one directly from inside the policy. A condition can contain two elements, a scope, and an expression. The expression is mandatory, but the scope is optional. A scope is a general attribute that is quickly checked before evaluating a more complex expression. You can create a scope at either the policy or condition level.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a New Condition Assigned to a Policy</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Control</guimenu><guisubmenu>Explorer</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the <guimenu>Policies</guimenu> accordion, and select the policy you want to create a new condition for.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel>), 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1862.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Create a new Condition assigned to this Policy</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Type in a <guilabel>Description</guilabel> for the condition. It must be unique to all the conditions.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1864.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1851.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Edit this Scope</guilabel>) in the <guilabel>Scope</guilabel> area to create a general expression based on a simple attribute, such as operating system version. Based on what you choose, different options display. Scope is optional.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Field</guilabel> to create criteria based on field values.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1865.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Count of</guilabel> to create criteria based on the count of something, such as the number of snapshots for a virtual machine, or the number of virtual machines on a host.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1866.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Tag</guilabel> to create criteria based on tags assigned to your resources. For example, you can check the power state of a virtual machine or see if it is tagged as production.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1867.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Find</guilabel> to seek a particular value, and then check a property. For example, finding the Admin account and checking that it is enabled. Use the following check commands:
					</para>
					<itemizedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para> 
								<guimenuitem>Check Any</guimenuitem>: The result is true if one or more of the find results satisfy the check condition.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> 
								<guimenuitem>Check All</guimenuitem>: All of the find results must match for a true result.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para> 
								<guimenuitem>Check Count</guimenuitem>: If the result satisfies the expression in check count, the result is true.
							</para>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1868.png" />
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</listitem>
					</itemizedlist>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Registry</guilabel> to create criteria based on registry values. For example, you can check if DCOM is enabled on a Windows System. Note that this applies only to Windows operating systems. Registry is only available if you are creating a VM Control Policy.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1869.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1863.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Commit expression element changes</guilabel>) to add the scope.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1851.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Edit this Expression</guilabel>) in the <guilabel>Expression</guilabel> area. Based on what you choose, options display as per the choices presented in the <guilabel>Scope</guilabel> area detailed above.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1863.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Commit Expression Element Changes</guilabel>) to add the expression.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In <guilabel>Notes</guilabel>, type in a detailed explanation of the condition.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Add</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			The condition is created and is assigned directly to the policy. Note that the condition can be assigned to other policies.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>