<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Control_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_simulate_Policy_Profiles_on_Virtual_Machines" remap="TID_14787">
	<title>Simulating Policy Profiles on Virtual Machines</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Simulate Policy Profiles on Virtual Machines</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Virtual Machines</guisubmenu></menuchoice>, select the virtual machines you need to evaluate.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1941.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Policy</guilabel>), and then click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1947.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guilabel>Policy Simulation</guilabel>).
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From the <guilabel>Select a Policy Profile to add</guilabel> dropdown, click the policy you need to apply to the selected virtual machines.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/1948.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				The virtual machine thumbnail displays in the <guilabel>Policy Simulation</guilabel> area.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A check sign in the lower right quadrant of the virtual thumbnail shows that the virtual machine passes policy.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						A minus sign in the lower right quadrant of the virtual thumbnail shows that the virtual machine fails policy.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click on a virtual machine in the <guilabel>Policy Simulation</guilabel> area to see its details.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Expand a policy profile by clicking on it to see its member policies and the status of the conditions.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Check <parameter>Show out of scope items</parameter> to show all conditions, whether or not the virtual machine passes the scope part of the condition. Uncheck it to hide conditions where the scope part fails.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Next to <parameter>Show policies</parameter>, check <parameter>Successful</parameter> to show policies that are passed and check <parameter>Failed</parameter> to see the policies that have failed. The default is to show both.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Items in green text passed the condition.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Items in red text failed the condition.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Items in red italics failed the condition, but do not change the outcome of the scope.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			If you evaluate multiple policy profiles, you can see both policy profiles and a tree expanding down to their conditions.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>