<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Registering_and_Updating_CloudForms_Management_Engine">
	<title>Registering and Updating CloudForms Management Engine</title> 
	<para>
		The <guibutton>Red Hat Updates</guibutton> page enables you to edit customer information, register appliances, and update appliances. Editing customer information enables you to determine the registration point, User ID, and password. Red Hat CloudForms prompts you to update the Server URL when updating the registration point to a local Red Hat Satellite. The <guilabel>Status of Available Servers</guilabel> area provides options to refresh, register, check for updates, and to update. The Red Hat Updates page enables the Content Delivery Network (CDN) to assign the necessary update packages to the CloudForms Management Engine Server.
	</para>
	<para>
		Using the <guibutton>Check For Updates</guibutton> task button, the CDN assigns any necessary update packages to your server and notifies you. Click <guibutton>Update</guibutton> and the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> packages install and update.
	</para>
	<para>
		Three steps are required for updating the CloudForms Management Engine Appliance: 
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Register the CloudForms Management Engine for updates if it is not already registered.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Update the CloudForms Management Engine Appliance.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Update other system packages.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</para>
	<para>
		The following tools are used during the update process: 
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para> 
					<literal>Yum</literal> provides package installation, updates, and dependency checking.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> 
					<literal>Red Hat Subscription Manager</literal> manages subscriptions and entitlements.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> 
					<literal>Red Hat Satellite Server</literal> runs at customer locations providing local system registration and updates from inside the customer's firewall.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
	<important>
		<para>
			The update worker synchronizes the VMDB with the status of available <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> content every 12 hours.
		</para>
	</important>
	<note>
		<para>
			Servers with the <guilabel>RHN Mirror</guilabel> role also act as a repository for other Appliances to pull <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> packages updates.
		</para>
	</note>
	<xi:include href="topics/Registering_Appliances.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	<xi:include href="topics/Updating_Appliances.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	<xi:include href="topics/Updating_the_Appliance_Operating_System.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
</chapter>