<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Enhancements">
	<title>Enhancements</title> 
	<para>
		The following enhancements are available with Red Hat CloudForms 4.0 (CFME 5.5).
	</para>
	<variablelist>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Entitlements</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Feature overview.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Event Switchboard</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Feature overview.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>	
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Pluggable Providers</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Feature overview.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>	
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Microsoft Azure Providers</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Feature overview.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Multi Tenancy</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Multi-tenancy support in Red Hat CloudForms offers several enhancements, with an ability to: 
					
				</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
						 support more than one organization with separate authentication and resource distribution. This includes the ability to have multi-level (nested) tenants.

						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
						 set quotas in the new tenant.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
						 support Role-based Access Control (RBAC), tagging, and approval sytem for tenants.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Red Hat Access Insights Plug-In</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					With this release, users can now access Red Hat Access Insights directly from the Red Hat CloudForms appliance web user interface. Red Hat Access Insights is an automated service that provides information that helps users to rapidly identify key issues in their Red Hat CloudForms deployment. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>		
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Red Hat OpenShift v3 Providers</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					The integration of Red Hat OpenShift v3 providers in Red Hat CloudForms provides support in the following areas, with an ability to:
				</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							view the topology of the OpenShift infrastructure (Inventory IUC1).
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							link any OpenShift inventory object to its hosting infrastructure (Cross Linking IUC2). Red Hat CloudForms can cross-link the OpenShift components to either their virtual or physical counterparts.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							generate a graphical topology map launched from the relationship area of the UI (Topology Widget IUC4).

						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							see the capacity that the RHEL Atomic Platform nodes have to offer (Capacity IUC5). 	
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							see how OpenShift Enterprise components (CPU, Memory, Storage &amp; Networking) are utilized (Utilization IUC6).
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							deliver fleecing images (IUC9).
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							have a dashboard showing details of your OpenShift Enterprise infrastructure (Dashboard IUC10).
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							receive events from OpenShift (Events EUC2).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>	
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Self Service Portal</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Users can better manage services and resources, using a UI with widgets, dashboard controls and feedback. This enhancement supports,

				</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							graphic images and html text description on the services.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							presentation of dialogs when a service is ordered.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							management of deployed services (My Services). 
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							catalog categories, branding, and authentication. 
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>				
	</variablelist>
</chapter>

