<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Navigating_the_Console" remap="TID_20178">
	<title>Navigating the Console</title>
	<figure>
		<title>CloudForms Management Engine's Main Navigation Menu</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2118.png" />
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	</figure>
	<orderedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Primary Navigation Bar
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Secondary Navigation Bar
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</orderedlist>
	<para>
		Click an item on the Primary Navigation Bar to go to that category. Then, you can click on a secondary item to refine the type of function.
	</para>
	<para>
		The Console consists of the following items on the Primary Navigation Bar:
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu> uses Really Simple Syndication (RSS) feeds and charts to display information on your virtual enterprise devices. It also includes reports both out of the box and custom.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Services</guimenu> provides a view of all of your discovered Catalogs of services and Workloads (Virtual Machines and Cloud Instances combined).
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Clouds</guimenu> enables you to see your Cloud Providers, Availability Zones, Cloud Tenants, Hardware Flavors, Security Groups, Cloud Instances, and Stacks.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu> enables you to see your Virtualization Providers, Clusters, Hosts, Virtual Machines, Resource Pools, Datastores, Repositories, and PXE Servers. You can also manage your infrastructure configuration through Configuration Management.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Control</guimenu> manages your policies through the Explorer, Simulation, Import/Export and the Log tabs. It further defines your policies by using Events, Conditions, and Actions.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Automate</guimenu> provides models for process integration and adaptive automation for events and activities.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guimenu>Optimize</guimenu> enables you to identify bottlenecks and plan placement of Virtual Machines.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<para>
		In addition to the items on the navigation bar, you can also use <guimenu>Configure</guimenu> to manage the user interface, create tags, set server, database and SmartProxy options, administer users, and update the software and view the documentation.
	</para>
</section>