<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_view_capacity_and_utilization_charts_for_a_Virtual_Machine" remap="TID_15168">
	<title>Viewing Capacity and Utilization Charts for a Virtual Machine</title>
	<para>
		You can view capacity and utilization data for virtual machines that are part of a cluster. Note that daily charts only include full days of data. If all 24 data points for a day are not available, daily charts are not displayed. For some capacity and utilization data, <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> calculates and shows trend lines in the charts which are created using linear regression. The calculation uses the capacity and utilization data collected by <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> during the interval you specify.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			You must have a server with network visibility to your provider assigned the server role of <guilabel>Capacity &amp; Utilization Collector</guilabel> to use this feature.
		</para>
		<para>
			The virtual machine must be powered on to collect the data.
		</para>
	</note>
	<procedure>
		<title>To View Capacity and Utilization Charts for a Virtual Machine</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Virtual Machines</guisubmenu></menuchoice>, click the accordion that you want to view capacity data for.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the item you want to view.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Monitoring)</guibutton>, and then 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Utilization)</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Interval</guilabel>, select to view <guimenuitem>Daily</guimenuitem>, <guimenuitem>Hourly</guimenuitem>, or <guimenuitem>Most Recent Hour</guimenuitem> data points. When choosing <guimenuitem>Daily</guimenuitem>, you can also select the <guimenuitem>Date</guimenuitem>, and how far back you want to go from that date. When selecting <guimenuitem>Hourly</guimenuitem>, you can select the date for which you want to view hourly data. If you are using <guimenuitem>Time Profiles</guimenuitem>, you will be able to select that as an option, also.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2246.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Compare to</guilabel>, select <guimenuitem>Parent Host</guimenuitem> or <guimenuitem>Parent Cluster</guimenuitem>. The capacity and utilization charts for both items will show simultaneously.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2247.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<note>
		<para>
			Daily charts only include full days of data. This means <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> does not show daily data for a day without a complete 24 data point range for a day.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>