<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Reports">
	<title>Reports</title> 
	<para>
		Click the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> accordion under <menuchoice><guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu><guisubmenu>Reports</guisubmenu></menuchoice> to see a list of reports available. These reports have been constructed to help you view the most commonly requested and significant data. From here, you can also create reports if you have appropriate access. <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> provides a large group of default reports organized into categories. Each category has its own set of subfolders.
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Configuration Management</guilabel> to see hardware, application, network, service, user account, operating system, and snapshot information for all of your items.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Migration Readiness</guilabel> to see information specifically related to items required to migrate a virtual machine.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Operations</guilabel> to look at free space on registered and unregistered virtual machines, to see power states for virtual machines, and see which offline virtual machines have snapshots or have never been analyzed. You are also provided with reports specifically related to the operation of <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname>, such as user ids and snapshots taken by <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname>.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>VM Sprawl</guilabel> to check on usage information and disk waste.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> to see virtual machine, folder, and cluster relationships.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Events</guilabel> to view operations and configuration management events.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Performance by Asset Type</guilabel> to see a report on the performance of your virtual infrastructure. You must be capturing capacity and utilization data to get this information.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Running Processes</guilabel> to view the information on processes running on a virtual machine. You must have domain credentials entered for the zone to collect the info for these reports, and the virtual machine must have been analyzed at least once.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Trending</guilabel> shows projections of datastore capacity and host CPU and memory use.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Provisioning</guilabel> shows provisioning activity based on the approver, datastore, requester, and virtual machine.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist> 
	<section id="sect-Running_Reports">
		<title>Running Reports</title> 
		<para>
			There are two different ways to generate a report: either scheduling the report, or manually by clicking the report generation button on the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> page. <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> uses interactive report generation so that reports are placed on a queue. A visual indicator of the reports status is shown. All reports are automatically saved so that they can be downloaded and analyzed later.
		</para>
		<xi:include href="topics/To_generate_a_single_report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_schedule_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_modify_a_report_schedule.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/To_run_a_scheduled_report_immediately.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
	<section id="sect-Viewing_Reports">
		<title>Viewing Reports</title> 
		<para>
			Once you have created a schedule for a report, you can view it at any time after the first scheduled time has occurred.
		</para>
		<procedure>
			<title>To View a Report</title>
			<step>
				<para>
					Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Cloud Intelligence</guimenu><guisubmenu>Reports</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click the <guimenu>Saved Reports</guimenu> accordion or the <guimenu>Reports</guimenu> accordion.
				</para>
			</step>
			<step>
				<para>
					Click on the instance of the report you want to view.
				</para>
			</step>
		</procedure>
		<xi:include href="topics/Changing_Report_Views.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Report_Download_Buttons.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Downloading_a_Report.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
		<xi:include href="topics/Showing_a_Report_in_Full_Screen.xml" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" />
	</section>
</chapter>