<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Adding_a_Microsoft_System_Center_Virtual_Machine_Manager_Provider" remap="TID_44296">
	<title>Adding a Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager Provider</title>
	<para>
		After initial installation and creation of a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> environment, add a Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager provider to the appliance.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Add a Provider</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Providers</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Configuration)</guibutton>, then click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1848.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject><guibutton>(Add a New Infrastructure Provider)</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> of the provider to add. The <guilabel>Name</guilabel> is how the device is labeled in the console.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select <guilabel>Microsoft System Center VMM</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Type</guilabel> list.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enter the <guilabel>Host Name (or IPv4 or IPv6 address)</guilabel> of the provider.
			</para>
			<important>
				<para>
					The <guilabel>Host Name</guilabel> must use a unique fully qualified domain name.
				</para>
			</important>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select <guilabel>Kerberos</guilabel> or <guilabel>Basic (SSL)</guilabel> from the <guilabel>Security Protocol</guilabel> list. The default security protocol is Kerberos.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				If you selected <guilabel>Kerberos</guilabel> as the security protocol, enter the <guilabel>Realm</guilabel> to which the Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager belongs: for example, <replaceable>www.example.com</replaceable>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Select the appropriate <guilabel>Zone</guilabel> for the provider. By default, the zone is set to <guilabel>default</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				In the <guilabel>Credentials</guilabel> area, under <guilabel>Default</guilabel>, provide the login credentials required for the Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager administrative user:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Enter the user name in the <guilabel>User ID</guilabel> field.
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							A user name under the Kerberos security protocol must be in the format <replaceable>name@realm</replaceable>.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Enter the user password in the <guilabel>Password</guilabel> field.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Confirm the user password in the <guilabel>Verify Password</guilabel> field.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guilabel>Validate</guilabel> to confirm that the CloudForms Management Engine can connect to the Microsoft System Center Virtual Machine Manager using the user name and password.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guilabel>Save</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>