<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Host_Virtual_Summary" remap="TID_15330">
	<title>Host Virtual Summary</title>
	<para>
		Clicking on a specific host shows the Hosts Virtual Thumbnail and an <emphasis>operating system-sensitive</emphasis> screen of host information, called the Host Summary. Where applicable, click on a subcategory of the Host Summary to see more detail on that section.
	</para>
	<para>
		A <guilabel>Refresh</guilabel> provides some basic information on the Host. To get more detail, enter credentials for the host and perform a SmartState Analysis.
	</para>
	<para>
		The Summary divides into the following categories.
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Properties</guilabel> include information such as base operating system, hostname, IP addresses, devices attached to the system, and storage adapters. Some categories can be clicked on for additional detail. For example, click <guilabel>Network</guilabel> to view the network adapters connected to the host.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2227.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> include information on the provider, cluster, datastores, resource pools, and installed virtual machines.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2228.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Security</guilabel> shows the number of users, groups, patches installed, and firewall rules on the host. Click on any of these items to see further details.
			</para>
			<note>
				<para>
					Run a SmartState Analysis on the host to retrieve this information.
				</para>
			</note> 
			<!--mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2229.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject-->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Storage Relationships</guilabel> shows the relationship the host has to LUNs, volumes, and file shares. The <guilabel>Storage Inventory Role</guilabel> must be enabled in the zone for these items to be populated.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel> shows the number of packages and services installed. Click on any of these items to see more details.
			</para>
			<note>
				<para>
					Run a SmartState Analysis on the host to retrieve this information.
				</para>
			</note>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2230.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Smart Management</guilabel> shows all tags assigned to this host.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Authentication Status</guilabel> shows all the types of credentials entered for this host and the whether those credentials are valid.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>