<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Instance_or_Image_Summary" remap="TID_21646">
	<title>Instance or Image Summary</title>
	<para>
		When you click on a specific instance or image, you will see the <guilabel>Virtual Thumbnail</guilabel>, and an <emphasis>operating system-specific</emphasis> screen of the item, called the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>. Where applicable, click on a subcategory of the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> to see more detail on that section.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			When you perform a SmartState Analysis on an instance or image, you get more detailed information in these categories:
		</para>
	</note>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Properties</guilabel> include information such as the base operating system, hostname, IP addresses, instance vendor, cloud resources, and snapshots. This includes the ability to analyze multiple partitions, multiple disks, Linux logical volumes, extended partitions, and Windows drives. Some categories can be clicked on for additional detail. For example, click <guilabel>Container</guilabel> to view notes associated with an instance.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2167.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Lifecycle</guilabel> shows the date of discovery and the last analysis. If a retirement date or owner has been set, these display as well.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2168.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> include information on the instance's cloud provider, genealogy such as parent and child instances, and drift.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2169.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>VMsafe</guilabel> shows properties of the VMsafe agent if it is enabled.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2170.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Compliance</guilabel> shows the status of system compliance checks and history of past checks.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Power Management</guilabel> displays the current power state, last boot time, and last power state change. <guilabel>State Changed On</guilabel> is the date that the instance last changed its power state. This is a container view of the power state, therefore a restart of the operating system does not cause the container power state to change and does not update this value.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2172.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Security</guilabel> includes information on users and groups.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2173.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel> includes information on applications, services, packages, init processes, and files. This section changes depending on the base operating system.
			</para> 
			<!--			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2174.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject> -->
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Diagnostics</guilabel> provides a link to viewing running processes and the information from the latest collected event logs.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Smart Management</guilabel> shows all tags assigned to this instance.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>