<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Storage_Support_Notes_about_Analyzing_from_RHEVM_3.0" remap="TID_15131">
	<title>SmartState Analysis on Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager 3.0 - Storage Support Notes</title>
	<para>
		There are two additional steps required to perform a SmartState Analysis on Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager 3.0 using iSCSI or FCP storage. NFS storage does not have these requirements.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<step>
			<para>
				Enable DirectLUN support for the host and <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance that performs the analysis.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Enable DirectLUN on host.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Enable DirectLUN on the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance. To do this, edit the desired Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization storage and get the LUNID value. Then, on the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance virtual machine in the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization user interface, right-click and select <menuchoice><guilabel>Edit</guilabel> <guilabel>Custom Properties</guilabel></menuchoice> and enter the following in the <guilabel>Custom Properties</guilabel> edit box: 
						<screen>directlun=&lt;LUN ID&gt;:readonly</screen> If you have multiple storage domains separate them by a comma, similar to: 
						<screen>directlun=&lt;LUN ID 1&gt;:readonly,&lt;LUN ID 2&gt;:readonly,&lt;LUN ID N&gt;:readonly</screen>
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							The <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance must reside in the same data center as the storage you are trying to connect. If you have multiple data centers with iSCSI or FCP storage, you need a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance in each data center to support virtual machine scanning.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Set Server Relationship - This is required to allow the virtual machine SmartState analysis job to determine which data center a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance is running and therefore identify what storage it has access to in a Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization environment.
			</para>
			<substeps>
				<step>
					<para>
						After setting up a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance and performing a refresh of the Provider, find the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance in the <guilabel>Virtual Machine</guilabel> accordion list and view its summary screen.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Click 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/1847.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Configuration)</guibutton>, and then 
						<inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/2146.png" />
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject><guibutton>(Edit Server Relationship)</guibutton>
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Select the server that relates to this instance of the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance.
					</para>
				</step>
			</substeps>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>