<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Storage_Support_Notes_about_Analyzing_from_RHEVM_3.1" remap="TID_15130">
	<title>SmartState Analysis on Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager 3.1 and Above - Storage Support Notes</title>
	<para>
		Note the following requirements when performing SmartState Analysis on Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager 3.1 and above.
	</para>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title>NFS</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> appliance requires a mount to the NFS datastore.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title>iSCSI / FCP</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				For <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</productname> 3.1 and 3.2, clusters must use full <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Linux</productname> hosts and not <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</productname> Hypervisor hosts. You can use either type of host in <productname>Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization</productname> 3.3 and above.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				Each <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance performing SmartState Analysis requires sharable, non-bootable DirectLUN access to each attached iSCSI/FCP storage domain. In order to perform smart analysis, the appliance must mount the data storage as a DirectLUN disk.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				A <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance <emphasis>must</emphasis> reside in each datacenter with the iSCSI / FCP storage type.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<itemizedlist>
		<title>Other Notes</title>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Set Server Relationship</guilabel> option enables the VM SmartState Analysis job to determine the datacenter where a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance is running and thus to identify what storage it has access to in a RHEV environment.
			</para>
			<procedure>
				<step>
					<para>
						After setting up a <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance and performing a refresh of the provider, find the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance in the <guilabel>Virtual Machine</guilabel> accordion list and view its summary screen.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Click <menuchoice><guimenu>Configuration</guimenu> <guisubmenu>Edit Server Relationship</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
					</para>
				</step>
				<step>
					<para>
						Select the server that relates to this instance of the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> Appliance.
					</para>
				</step>
			</procedure>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
	<important>
		<para>
			If you attach a DirectLUN disk after configuring the <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> database, access the Appliance in a terminal and run <command>pvscan</command> to detect the DirectLUN disk. Alternatively, in <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> 5.2.1 and above, you can restart the Appliance to detect the disk automatically.
		</para>
	</important>
</section>