<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_create_a_Virtual_Machine_or_Template_Filter" remap="TID_15114">
	<title>Creating a Virtual Machine or Template Filter</title>
	<procedure>
		<title>To Create a Virtual Machine Or Template Filter</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to menu:Infrastructure[Virtual Machines].
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Go to the [label]#VMs# or [label]#Templates# accordion.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>All VMs</guibutton> or <guibutton>All Templates</guibutton>, then click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/2125.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Advanced Search)</guibutton> to open the expression editor.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Use the expression editor to choose the appropriate options for your criteria. Based on what you choose, different options will show.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						For all of the types of searches, you have the options of creating an alias and requested user input. Select <guilabel>Use Alias</guilabel> to create a user friendly name for the search. If you are requested user input for the search, this text will show in the dialog box where the input is requested.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>Field</guibutton> to create criteria based on field values.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2126.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>Count of</guibutton> to create criteria based on the count of something, such as the number of snapshots for a virtual machine, or the number of virtual machines on a host.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2127.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>Tag</guibutton> to create criteria based on tags assigned to your virtual infrastructure, such as for power states or production tagging.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2128.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>Registry</guibutton> to create criteria based on registry values, such as the DCOM status of a Windows system. Note this criteria applies only to Windows operating systems.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2129.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Click <guibutton>Find</guibutton> to seek a particular value, and then check a property.
					</para>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2130.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1863.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Commit Expression Element Changes)</guibutton> to add the expression.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Type in a name for the search expression in <guilabel>Save this VM</guilabel> search as. (Note that this title depends on the type of resource you are searching.) To set the filter to show globally, check <guilabel>Global Filter</guilabel>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click <guibutton>Save</guibutton>.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Result:</title>
		<para>
			The filter is saved and will show in the <guilabel>My Filters</guilabel> area of the <guilabel>Filter</guilabel> accordion. If you checked <guilabel>Global Filter</guilabel>, the filter will show there.
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>