<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="To_view_the_timeline_for_a_Virtual_Machine_or_Template" remap="TID_15170">
	<title>Viewing the Virtual Machine or Template Timeline</title>
	<para>
		View the timeline of events for a virtual machine or template if registered to a Host.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To View the Timeline for a Virtual Machine Or Template</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to menu:Infrastructure[Virtual Machines].
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the virtual machine to view the timeline.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Monitoring)</guibutton>, and then 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1995.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Timelines)</guibutton> on the taskbar.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Options</guilabel>, customize the period of time to display, and the types of events to view.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2166.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Interval</guilabel> dropdown to select hourly or daily data points.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Date</guilabel> to type the date of the timeline to display.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If viewing a daily timeline, use <guilabel>Show</guilabel> to set how many days back to go. The maximum history is 31 days.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The three <guilabel>Event Group</guilabel> dropdowns allow selection of different event groups to display. Each has its own color.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						From the <guilabel>Level</guilabel> dropdown, select either a <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> event or a <guilabel>Detail</guilabel> list of events. For example, the detail level of a <guilabel>Power On</guilabel> event might include the power on request, the starting event, and the actual Power On event. If you select <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>, you only see the <guilabel>Power On</guilabel> event in the timeline.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To see more detail on an item in the timeline, click on it. A balloon appears with a clickable link to the resource.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>