<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Viewing_the_Host_Timeline" remap="TID_15325">
	<title>Viewing the Host Timeline</title>
	<para>
		View the timeline of events for the virtual machines registered to a host.
	</para>
	<procedure>
		<title>To View the Timeline for a Host</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Hosts</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click the Host to view the timeline.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Monitoring)</guibutton>, and then 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1995.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Timelines)</guibutton> or from the Host Accordion, click <menuchoice><guimenu>Properties</guimenu> <guisubmenu>Timelines</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Options</guilabel>, customize the period of time to display and the types of events to see.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Show</guilabel> to select types of events to show on the timeline.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use the <guilabel>Interval</guilabel> dropdown to select hourly or daily data points.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Use <guilabel>Date</guilabel> to type the date the timeline displays.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						If you select to view a daily timeline, use <guilabel>Show</guilabel> to set how many days back to go. The maximum history is 31 days. If selecting <guilabel>Hourly</guilabel>, select the interval to see.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						From the <guilabel>Level</guilabel> dropdown, select either a <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> event or a <guilabel>Detail</guilabel> list of events. For example, the detail level of a <guilabel>Power On</guilabel> event might include the power on request, the starting event, and the actual <guilabel>Power On</guilabel> event. If you select <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>, only the Power On event appears in the timeline.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The three <guilabel>Event Group</guilabel> dropdowns allow selection of different groups of events to display. Each group has its own color.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				To see more detail on an item in the timeline, click on it. A balloon appears with a clickable link to the resource.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
</section>