<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Insight_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Viewing_Capacity_and_Utilization_Charts_for_a_Datastore" remap="TID_15367">
	<title>Viewing Capacity and Utilization Charts for a Datastore</title>
	<para>
		You can view capacity and utilization data for a datastore.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para> 
			<productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> requires network visibility to your provider assigned the server role of <guilabel>Capacity &amp; Utilization Collector</guilabel> to enable this feature.
		</para>
	</note>
	<procedure>
		<title>To View Capacity and Utilization Charts for a Datastore</title>
		<step>
			<para>
				Navigate to <menuchoice><guimenu>Infrastructure</guimenu><guisubmenu>Datastores</guisubmenu></menuchoice>, then click the Datastore that you want to view Capacity and Utilization data for.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				Click 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> <guibutton>(Monitoring)</guibutton>, and then 
				<inlinemediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/1994.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</inlinemediaobject> (<guibutton>Utilization</guibutton>) or from the Datastore Accordion, click <menuchoice><guimenu>Properties</guimenu> <guisubmenu>Capacity &amp; Utilization</guisubmenu></menuchoice>.
			</para>
		</step>
		<step>
			<para>
				From <guilabel>Interval</guilabel>, select to view hourly or daily data points and the dates to view data. Use <guilabel>VM Types to Include</guilabel> to include only managed/registered, managed/unregistered, or unmanaged virtual machines. The following definitions will be helpful.
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<emphasis>Managed/Registered VM</emphasis> - A virtual machine connected to a host and exists in the VMDB. Also, a template connected to a management system and exists in the VMDB.
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							Templates cannot be connected to a Host.
						</para>
					</note>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<emphasis>Managed/Unregistered VM</emphasis> - A virtual machine or template that resides on a repository or is no longer connected to a management system or host and exists in the VMDB. A virtual machine previously considered registered might become unregistered if the virtual machine is removed from management system inventory.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para> 
						<emphasis>Not Managed</emphasis> - Files discovered on a datastore that do not have a virtual machine associated with them in the VMDB. These files might be registered to a management system that <productname>CloudForms Management Engine</productname> does not have configuration information. Possible causes might be the management system has not been discovered or the management system has been discovered but no security credentials are provided.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				Use <guilabel>Time Profiles</guilabel> to select a time range for the data.
			</para>
		</step>
	</procedure>
	<para>
		The Capacity &amp; Utilization Collector charts are displayed.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			Daily charts only include full days of data. If a day does not include all the 24 data points for a day, the data does not show for that day.
		</para>
	</note>
</section>