<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE section PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "../Managing_Inventory_and_Infrastructure.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="Virtual_Machine_or_Template_Summary" remap="TID_15174">
	<title>Virtual Machine or Template Summary</title>
	<para>
		When you click on a specific virtual machine or template, you will see the <guilabel>Virtual Thumbnail</guilabel>, and an <emphasis>operating system-specific</emphasis> screen of the item, called the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel>. Where applicable, click on a subcategory of the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> to see more detail on that section.
	</para>
	<note>
		<para>
			When you perform a SmartState Analysis on a virtual machine or template, you get more detailed information in these categories.
		</para>
	</note>
	<itemizedlist>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Properties</guilabel> include information such as the base operating system, hostname, IP addresses, Virtual Machine vendor, CPU Affinity, devices attached to the system, and snapshots. This includes the ability to analyze multiple partitions, multiple disks, Linux logical volumes, extended partitions, and Windows drives. Some categories can be clicked on for additional detail. For example, click <guilabel>Container</guilabel> to view notes associated with a virtual machine.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2167.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Lifecycle</guilabel> shows the date of discovery and the last analysis. If a retirement date or owner has been set, these display as well.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2168.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Relationships</guilabel> include information on the parent host, genealogy such as parent and child virtual machines, and drift.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2169.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Storage Relationships</guilabel> shows relationships to Filers, LUNs, Volumes and File Shares.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>VMsafe</guilabel> shows properties of the <productname>VMsafe</productname> agent if it is enabled.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2170.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Normal Operating Ranges</guilabel> shows the values the normal operating range for this virtual machine. These statistics are used in calculating right sizing recommendations.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2171.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Power Management</guilabel> displays the current power state, last boot time, and last power state change. <guilabel>State Changed On</guilabel> is the date that the virtual machine last changed its power state. This is a container view of the power state, therefore a restart of the operating system does not cause the container power state to change and will not update this value.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2172.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Security</guilabel> includes information on users, groups, and security patches. Recall that the items shown on the <guilabel>Summary</guilabel> screen change based on the guest operating system.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2173.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Configuration</guilabel> includes information on applications, services, packages, and init processes. This section changes depending on the base operating system.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2174.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Datastore Allocation Summary</guilabel> shows how many and how much disk space has been allocated to this virtual machine as well as disk alignment and thin provisioning information.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Datastore Actual Usage Summary</guilabel> shows how much disk and memory the virtual machine is actually using.
			</para>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata align="center" fileref="images/2175.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Diagnostics</guilabel> provides a link to viewing running processes and the information from the latest collected event logs.
			</para>
		</listitem>
		<listitem>
			<para> 
				<guilabel>Smart Management</guilabel> shows all tags assigned to this virtual machine.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</itemizedlist>
</section>